<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Kiran Ganji</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Kiran Ganji</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear regression - Must knows</title>
      <link>/blog/linear-regression---must-knows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/linear-regression---must-knows/</guid>
      <description>Linear regression is one of the easiest and first taught models. But there is more to the algorithm than it appears. Given its simplicity, it is often abused. In this article, let’s get some facts straight about the algorithm.
Must-knows about linear regression:
Linear regression derives a trend line that best fits the dataThere should be linear relationship between response variable &amp;amp; predictors and predictors shouldn’t be correlatedResiduals (Actual - Fitted) should be normally distributed, have constant variance and shouldn’t be autocorrelated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptocurrency analysis - What to trade?</title>
      <link>/blog/cryptocurrency-analysis---what-to-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cryptocurrency-analysis---what-to-trade/</guid>
      <description>I recently developed a rudimentary method to identify the potential cryptocurrencies to BUY and trade. I did this exercise for Gramener’s blog. Reposting the same below. The actual article that I wrote can be found here
I followed the below steps:
Scraped the entire trading history of each of the cryptocurrencies available at CoinMarketCapFiltered cryptocurrencies based on Market capital, moving averages and PricesRan a greedy search to identify the combination of moving averages that yielded maximum profits on cross over points trading strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel must knows</title>
      <link>/blog/excel-must-knows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/excel-must-knows/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Excel is a godsend for anyone who want to analyze and visualize data. In this article let’s look at some of the must-knows of excel to get started.
Anyone who wishes to master excel should know the following aspects:
Navigation using shortcuts - Boosts productivity by atleast 20%Pivot tables - Aggregates and unlocks the relationships between variablesFormulas - Help derive new metrics, define KPIs, transform and quantify variablesVisualization - Make sense of the data through a visual aidSolver - Advanced optimization with easeAlt, Ctrl and Shift are your friends when it comes to navigating around in excelKeyboard shortcuts help you move around in excel without using mouse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Data Science</title>
      <link>/blog/getting-started-with-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/getting-started-with-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Knowing SQL, R/Python, Excel &amp;amp; Powerpoint will get the data science engine startedData scientist is the sexiest job of 21st century. Below given are some tools that a newbie in data science should get familiar with:
Excel - Can’t stress enough, but this is a must and should!SQL, R, Python - R (or) Python should suffice. It never hurts to have both in pocket.Power point, Tableau, Power BISublime text editor, Dropbox paperDatabases &amp;amp; Websites are crucial sources of dataAlmost all the companies, small and big, keep their data in databases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>