<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started on Kiran Ganji</title>
    <link>/categories/getting-started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started on Kiran Ganji</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel must knows</title>
      <link>/blog/excel-must-knows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/excel-must-knows/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Excel is a godsend for anyone who want to analyze and visualize data. In this article let’s look at some of the must-knows of excel to get started.
Anyone who wishes to master excel should know the following aspects:
Navigation using shortcuts - Boosts productivity by atleast 20%Pivot tables - Aggregates and unlocks the relationships between variablesFormulas - Help derive new metrics, define KPIs, transform and quantify variablesVisualization - Make sense of the data through a visual aidSolver - Advanced optimization with easeAlt, Ctrl and Shift are your friends when it comes to navigating around in excelKeyboard shortcuts help you move around in excel without using mouse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Data Science</title>
      <link>/blog/getting-started-with-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/getting-started-with-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Knowing SQL, R/Python, Excel &amp;amp; Powerpoint will get the data science engine startedData scientist is the sexiest job of 21st century. Below given are some tools that a newbie in data science should get familiar with:
Excel - Can’t stress enough, but this is a must and should!SQL, R, Python - R (or) Python should suffice. It never hurts to have both in pocket.Power point, Tableau, Power BISublime text editor, Dropbox paperDatabases &amp;amp; Websites are crucial sources of dataAlmost all the companies, small and big, keep their data in databases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>